Guide to the James Perkins papers,1963-1969.
Perkins, James papers,1963-1969.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
James Perkins papers, 1963-1969.
3-10-1022
James Alfred, Perkins 1911-
44 cubic ft.
Correspondence, administrative papers, and reports.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The papers of James A. Perkins consist of correspondence, reports, administrative management forms and records, drafts of speeches, correspondence, notes of telephone conversations, memoranda for the record, substantive inter-office notes and memos, commission reports, departmental reports to the President, tape recordings, transcripts, broadsides, a phonodisc, and letters received by the President's Office concerning the events on campus in the Spring of 1969
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
James A. Perkins was born on October11, 1911 in Philadelphia, and attended the Germantown Friends' School. He graduated with high honors in 1934 from Swarthmore College, and received a doctorate in political science from Princeton in 1937. He remained at Princeton until 1941, first as an instructor of political science, later as an assistant professor and assistant director of the School of Public and International Affairs. During World War II., Perkins served in the Office of Price Administration and the Foreign Economic Administration. From 1945 to 1950, he was vice president of Swarthmore College. In 1950 he joined the Carnegie Corporation as an executive associate, and in 1951 became vice president. From 1951 to 1963, Perkins served as vice president of the Carnegie Corporation of New York and the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching. From 1963 to 1969, he served as the seventh president of Cornell University
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The James A. Perkins papers consist of the administrative papers of his presidency from 1963-1969; subjects include the issues of academic freedom and freedom of speech, the educational needs and sociological problems of black students in the university, and the establishment and maintenance of programs to facilitate black students' success; there is also extensive correspondence concerning trustee and alumni affairs, particularly regarding fund raising and university endowments; other topics include the funding of the Andrew Dickson White Professors-at-Large and other professorships and chairs, the construction and funding of new campus buildings, planning for and celebration of the Cornell Centennial of 1965, the College of Arts and Sciences Humanities Council, university research and government funded research, university relations with Ithaca New York and Tompkins County; also, Cornell Latin American Year, Cornell United Religious Work, Cornell Clubs; relations with the State University of New York (SUNY), the development of the Division of Biological Sciences, the Society for the Humanities, and the Cornell University Library rare book collections; also, relations between the Administration and the University Faculty, the Residential Club fire of 1967 and the six year Ph.D. Program; the funding and development of the Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art, and the separation of Cornell University and the Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory of Buffalo.
Topics also include anti-war protest relating to ROTC, the suppression of the distribution of "The Trojan Horse" and the resulting conflict between students and the administration; housing for students both on and off campus, the difficulties and emergency situations arising from student conduct, dissent, protest, and demonstrations, and the question of university governance particularly in the Spring of 1969. Organizations and corporations discussed include the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, the Carnegie Corporation, the Ford Foundation, the Rockefeller Foundation, the American Council on Education, the National Science Foundation, the Association of Colleges and Universities of the State of New York, the National Collegiate Athletic Association, the Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, the Cornell University Medical College and New York Hospital, Students for a Democratic Society (SDS), the United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, and United States Selective Service. Correspondents include Morton Adams, Eric Ashby, Max Black, James E. Allen, Kingman Brewster, McGeorge Bundy, Van Alan Clark, Dale R. Corson, Arthur H. Dean, Mary H. Donlon, Jean-Jacques Demorest, Mario Einaudi, Orville L. Freeman, Henry Guerlac, John W. Gardner, Jacob K. Javits, Herbert F. Johnson, George McT. Kahin, Alfred E. Kahn, Burnham Kelly, W. Keith Kennedy, Milton R. Konvitz, Sol M. Linowitz, Franklin A. Long, Deane W. Malott, Arthur M. Mizener, Chandler Morse, Steven Muller, Floyd R. Newman, and Jansen Noyes.
Other correspondents include John M. Olin, Spencer T. Olin, Charles E. Palm, Robert W. Purcell, Edgar M. Queeny, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Clinton Rossiter, Allan P. Sindler, Robert L. Sproull, James E. Turner, Maxwell M. Upson, and Harold D. Uris.
Also, reports of the President's Commission to Study the New York State College of Agriculture, the Commission of April 1968, the Commission of Undergraduate Education, and the Committee of Student Involvement in Decision Making.
Album with programs and photographs from Cornell University's Centennial, 1965.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Perkins, James Alfred,1911-; Adams, Morton, 1910-; Allen, James Edward.; Ashby, Eric, 1904-; Black, Max, 1909-; Brewster, Kingman, 1919-; Bundy, McGeorge.; Clark, Van Alan.; Corson, Dale R.; Dean, Arthur H.; Demorest, Jean-Jacques.; Donlon, Mary H., 1893-1977.; Einaudi, Mario, 1904-; Freeman, Orville L.; Gardner, John William, 1912-; Guerlac, Henry.; Javits, Jacob K. (Jacob Koppel), 1904-1986.; Johnson, Herbert F.; Kahin, George McTurnan.; Kahn, Alfred E.(Alfred Edward).; Kelly, Burnham.; Kennedy, W. Keith, 1919-; Konvitz, Milton Ridvas, 1905-; Linowitz, Sol M., 1913-; Long, Franklin A. 1910-; Malott, Deane W.(Deane Waldo), 1898-; Mizener, Arthur M.; Morse, Chandler.; Muller, Steven, 1927-; Newman, Floyd R.(Floyd Roy), 1890-1990.; Noyes, Jansen.; Olin, John M.; Olin, Spencer T.; Palm, Charles E.; Purcell, Robert W.; Queeny, Edgar M.(Edgar Montsanto), 1897-1968.; Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman.; Rossiter, Clinton Lawrence, 1917-1970.; Sindler, Allan P.; Sproull, Robert L.; Turner, James E.; Upson, Maxwell M.; Uris, Harold D.; Alfred P. Sloan Foundation.; American Council on Education.; Association of Colleges and Universities of the State of New York.; Carnegie Corporation.; Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory.; Cornell United Religious Work.; Cornell University--Administration.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University--Presidents.; Cornell University--Libraries.; Cornell University--Alumni and alumnae.; Cornell University--Finance.; Cornell University--Museums.; Cornell University Medical College--Administration.; Cornell University-New York Hospital School of Nursing.; Cornell University. Office of the President.; Cornell University. University Faculty.; Cornell University. Residential Club.; Cornell University. Board of Trustees.; Cornell University. Cornell Latin American year.; Cornell University. Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art.; Cornell University. Library.; Cornell University. Division of Biological Sciences.; Cornell University. Six-Year Ph.D. Program.; Cornell University. Commission to Study the New York State College of Agriculture.; Cornell University. Commission of April, 1968.; Cornell University. Commission on Undergraduate Education.; Cornell University. Committee on Student Involvement in Decision Making.; Cornell University. Medical College.; Ford Foundation.; National Collegiate Athletic Association.; National Science Foundation.; New York Hospital.; Rockefeller Foundation.; State University of New York.; Students for a Democratic Society.
Titles:
Trojan horse.
Subjects:
Academic freedom.; Women college students.; Athletics.; African American college students.; College students--Conduct of life.; Demonstrations.; Student movements; Student housing.; Peace movements.; Students--Political activity.; College presidents.; College administrators.
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See also James A. Perkins Papers, #3-10-3158.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
The records of the six years of the Perkins presidency are divided into three two-year series (1963-65, 1965-67, and 1967-69) and a fourth series spanning his presidency. The biannual periods are further divided into two groups: the first is derived from the organizational structure of Cornell University, following the hierarchy beginning with the Board of Trustees and continuing through the President's and Provost's Offices, the Offices of Vice Presidents and other administrative officials, the Cornell University Medical College, Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, the Deans of the statutory and endowed colleges and schools, departments, committees, commissions, and boards within the university. The second group is alphabetically arranged, and includes individuals, organizations, and topics both inside and outside the university. The fourth series, 1963-69 (primarily 1967-69), is topically arranged, and includes letters to the Office of the President concerning the events of the Spring of 1969, files pertaining to the state of the university in 1967-69 and its relations with trustees and alumni, records concerning the Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, the speeches of James A. Perkins, Presidential commission files and reports, annual reports to the president, transcripts, tape recordings, and other subjects
SERIES LIST
Series I. 1963-1965
Boxes 1-10
Series II. 1965-1967
Boxes 10-21
Series III. 1967-1969
Boxes 22-31
Series IV. 1963-1969
Boxes 31-44
Correspondence re Willard Straight Hall occupation and the events of Spring 1969/"Challenge to Governance"
James A. Perkins' Speeches, Writings, Reports, Printed Material
President's Committee to Study the New York State College of Agriculture at Cornell University
President's Committee on Student Involvement in Decision Making (Morison Commission)
Commission on Undergraduate Education
Special University Commission of April, 1968 (Williams Commission)
Tape Recordings
Transcripts
Phono Disc
Broadsides
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. 1963-1965
  - Board of Trustees., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Williams, Robin M.
  - Board of Trustees, General Correspondence., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Stamp, Neal R. Agenda.
  - Board of Trustees, General Correspondence., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Kahn, Alfred E.; Belcher, Donald R.
  - Board of Trustees, General Correspondence., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Rockefeller, Nelson A. Cornell University Charter Day celebration.
  - Cisler, Walker L., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Collyer, John L., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Dean, Arthur H., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Noyes, Jansen. Lafayette Book Collection; Centennial Campaign; Avalon Foundation Professorship in the Humanities.
  - Dean, Arthur H., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Upson, Maxwell M.; Purcell, Robert W. Lafayette Book Collection; Lincoln Center festivities.
  - Donlon, Mary H. Corson, Dale R.; Warren, Earl; Mackesey, Thomas W. Elbert Parr Tuttle Graduate Fellowships., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Donlon, Mary H., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Linowitz, Sol M.; Thomas, Felix; Noll, A. Robert; Keast, William R.; Dean, Arthur H. Centennial Campaign; Student conduct.
  - Grumann, LeRoy R., 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Roy Grumann Special Fund; Grumann Squash Courts.
  - Johnson, Herbert F. Kelly, Burnham; Olin, John M. Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art., 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Knight, John S., 1963-65 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Noyes, Jansen; Collyer, John L. Centennial Campaign; Center for International Studies.
  - Levis, J. Preston., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Student conduct.
  - Noyes, Jansen., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Olin, John M.; Noyes, Nicholas H.; Upson, Maxwell M. Centennial Campaign; Old Dominion Foundation.
  - Noyes, Nicholas H., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Clark, Van Alan. Lilly Foundation; Lilly Endowment; Centennial Campaign; Andrew Dickson White Professors at Large; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation Professorships.
  - Olin, John H., 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Queeny, Edgar M. Centennial Campaign; Veterinary Virus Research Institute.
  - Olin, Spencer T., 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Ripley, Joseph P., 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Joseph P. Ripley Endowment Fund.
  - Scheetz, Francis H., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Corson, Dale R. Academic freedom.
  - Severinghaus, Leslie R., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Student protest; Civil rights.
  - Upson, Maxwell M., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Russell, P. Dean. Division of Biological Sciences; Centennial Campaign; Cornell United Religious Work (CURW).
  - Syme, John P., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Dean, Arthur H.
  - Trustees, Correspondence. Will, Philip; Purcell, Robert W.; Clark, John M.; Adams, Morton; Griffis, Stanton; Schoellkopf, Paul A.; Bache, Harold L.; Dean, Arthur H.; Grohmann, H. Victor. Centennial Campaign; Freshman Center., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Trustees, Correspondence., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Clark, John M.; Hawley, John B.; Bache, Harold L.; Elmhirst, Leonard K.; Grohmann, H. Victor; Grumann, LeRoy R.; Mason, Birny; Queeny, Edgar M. Centennial Campaign.
  - Trustees, Correspondence. Bache, Harold L.; Grohmann, H. Victor; Will, Philip; Rogers, Adele. Centennial Campaign; Institutional planning., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Trustees, Correspondence., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Will, Philip; Clark, John M.; Grohmann, H. Victor; Bache, Harold L.; Kiplinger, Austin H. Centennial Campaign.
  - Trustees, Correspondence., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Purcell, Robert W.; Will, Philip; Noyes, Jansen; Griffis, Stanton; Newbury, George A.; Saperston, Alfred M.; Clark, John M.; Schoellkopf, Paul A.
  - Wood, Frederic C., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Dean, Arthur H.; Clark, John M.; Alexander, Robert E. Baker Laboratory.
  - Board of Trustees Executive Committee., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 30-32)
  - Board of Trustees Investment Committee., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
  - Board of Trustees Buildings and Properties Committee., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 35-36)
  - Board of Trustees Membership Committee., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Library Board., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Keast, William R.
  - Physical Education and Athletics Board., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - School of Education Administrative Board., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Willard Straight Hall, Board of Governors., 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Whiting, Edgar A.
  - Engineering Council., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Schultz, Andrew.
  - New York State College of Agriculture and Experiment Station Council., 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    King, Joseph P.; Palm, Charles E.; Adams, Morton; Steward, Frederick C.
  - New York State College of Home Economics Council., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Irish, Ruth F.
  - New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations Council., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Moore, David G.
  - College of Arts and Sciences Council., 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Brown, Stuart M.
  - Deans and Heads of Departments., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    Malott, Deane W.; Palm, Charles E.
  - News Bureau., 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    Tobin, Thomas L.
  - News Bureau Releases., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Academic Freedom Correspondence., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    Scheetz, Francis H.
  - Assistants to the President., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Bess, James L.; Williams, Frederic A.
  - President., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    Long, Franklin A.; Corson, Dale R. Institute for the Study of the University.
  - President., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    Chabot, Daniel C.; Alexander, John G.; Grumann, LeRoy R.; Pew, J. Howard; Pew, Joseph N. Sloan Foundation; President's residence; Synopsis of conversations or visits with/by James A Perkins.
  - President., 1963-65 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    Kidera, Robert A. Inauguration; President's retreat.
  - Reports of the President., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Staff Meetings., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - Staff Officers, Notices, Miscellaneous., 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Luckey, E. Hugh.
  - Mimeograph Notices to Staff., 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Malott, Deane W. Employee insurance.
  - President's Speeches., 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Speech Materials., 1964 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Kelly, Burnham. Cornell University Research Park; Ithaca urban renewal.
  - Planning and Policy Making., 1963 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Long Range Development Plan.
  - Provost., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Corson, Dale R.; Upson, Maxwell M.; Severinghaus, Leslie R. Student Employment Committee; College of Arts and Sciences, deanship; SUNY Master Plan; Appointment of Dale R. Corson.
  - Vice-Provost., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Mackesey, Thomas W. Andrew Dickson White Museum of Art; Housing; Dormitories; "Planning and Constructing University Facilities."
  - Vice-Provost., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Mackesey, Thomas W.; Donlon, Mary H. Housing; Cornell University Planning Office.
  - Vice-Provost., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Mackesey, Thomas W. Andrew Dickson White Museum of Art; Centennial Campaign; Center for Continuing Education (Proposal); Synchrotron; Freshman Center; Urban renewal.
  - Vice-Provost., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Mackesey, Thomas W. NASA; Reorganization of colleges; Student housing, off campus; Freshman Center; "The Bright Young Men," list.
  - Planning Operations in New England Universities., 1963 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Mackesey, Thomas W.
  - Planning Officer., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Egner, Anton J. Parking.
  - Vice President for Development., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Kidera, Robert A.; Johnson, Herbert F.; Zwingle, J.L. Johnson Foundation; Centennial Campaign; Corporate development; Fund raising; Internal publications.
  - Vice President for Development., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Zwingle, J.L. Corporate development; Fund raising.
  - Office for planning and Development., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Kidera, Robert A.
  - Office for Planning and Development., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Kidera, Robert A.; Minogue, Joe; Ramin, Richard M. Olin Foundation; Foundation gifts.
  - Alumni Directory., 1965 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Cornell University Council., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Kidera, Robert A.; Zwingle, J.L. Cornell University Board of Trustees.
  - Parents' Program., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Donlon, Mary H.
  - Vice President for Research., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Malott, Deane W.; Hastie, John W.; Corson, Dale R.; Long, Franklin A.; Cisler, Walker L.; Rogers, Thomas R. Cornell University Research Foundation, Inc.; American Institute of Indian Studies.
  - Vice President for Research., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Long, Franklin A.; Rogers, Thomas R. Arecibo; National Science Foundation.
  - Vice President for Research., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Long, Franklin A.; Rogers, Thomas R.; Kennedy, Robert F. Synchrotron.
  - Vice President for Business., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Burton, John E. Synchrotron.
  - Buildings and Properties., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Alexander, Robert E.
  - Space and Room Requirements., 1963 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Housing Research Center., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Jones, Barclay G.; Beyer, Glenn H. Cornell University Center for Housing and Environmental Studies.
  - Campus Store., 1965 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Peterson, Arthur H.
  - Safety Division and Traffic Control., 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Board on Traffic Control., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Peterson, Arthur H. Parking.
  - Residential Halls, Dormitories., 1956-1962 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Purchasing Dept., 1960-1964 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Sage Chapel., 1963 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Vice President for Student Affairs., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    Summerskill, John; Barlow, Mark. Disadvantaged students.
  - Vice President for Academic Affairs., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    Keast, William R. Undergraduate education; Six Year Ph.D. Program.
  - Treasurer., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    Durland, Lewis H. Portfolio.
  - Treasurer., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    Durland, Lewis H.; Horn, Robert T.; White, Andrew Strong. Portfolio.
  - Treasurer., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    Durland, Lewis H.; Peterson, Arthur H.; Noyes, Nicholas H.; Corson, Dale R. Portfolio.
  - Treasurer., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    Durland, Lewis H.; Noyes, Nicholas H. Portfolio.
  - Academic Budgets., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Academic Budgets., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    Budget Planning Committee.
  - Budget Director., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    McKeegan, Paul L.; Donlon, Mary H, Faculty salaries.
  - Budget Director., 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    McKeegan, Paul L.; Roberts, E.R.; Dean, Arthur H.
  - Cornell University Budget., 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 47-48)
  - Cornell University Budget., 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Tuition and Fees., 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of the Corporation and University Counsel., 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Stamp, Neal R.; Morrison, Philip; McFaddin, Harrison D.; Pew, Joseph N.; Hollister, Solomon C.; Palm, Charles E. NASA; Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory; Arecibo; Synchrotron; Grants.
  - Secretary of the Corporation and University Counsel., 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Stamp, Neal R.; Malott, Deane W.; Fahnestock, William; Cisler, Walker L.; Newman, Floyd R. Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory; George A. Rumsey Scholarship Plan; "United Share Plan."
  - Director of Admissions., 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Snickenberger, Walter A.
  - Secondary Schools Committee., 1964 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Dickason, Donald G.
  - Applicants for Admission., 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Registrar., 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
  - Registration and Schedules Committee., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Commencement., 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
  - University Printer., 1964 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Controller., 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Peterson, Arthur H.; Johns, Hunna. Community Transit System; "Market Value Plan."
  - Dean of Students., 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Davis, Stanley W.; Nichols, Mary D. Trojan Horse; Housing policies for women.
  - International Student Office., 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Kizilbash, Mehdi; Williams, David B. Foreign student enrollment.
  - Students., 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Friedman, Paul L. Student organizations.
  - Fraternities and Interfraternity Council., 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Orientation Program., 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Kennedy, Robert F. Freshman Convocation.
  - Student Government., 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Henning, Dyle G.
  - Student Government., 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Student Government., 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Henning, Dyle G.; Friedman, Paul L.; Gunning, David H.
  - Cornell Daily Sun., 1965 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Weill, James D.
  - Women's Student Government Association., 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Press, Barbara.
  - WVBR., 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Proctor., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    George, Lowell T.
  - Secretary of the University., 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Baldwin, Frank C.
  - University Press., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Howley, Roger.
  - Rare Book Dinner., 1964 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Cornell University Libraries, Olin and Mann., 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    McCarthy, Stephen A.; Reichmann, Felix; Mennen, William G.; White, E.B.; Odelberg, W. Lafayette Book Collection; Cornell University Library Board.